Based on one hell of a true story.
The World's Fastest Indian is a drama, adventure,
history film directed by Roger Donaldson.
The life story of New Zealander Burt Munro, who spent years building a 1920 Indian motorcycle—a bike
which helped him set the land-speed world record at Utah's Bonneville Salt Flats in 1967.
Burt Munro, played by Anthony Hopkins.
Marty Dickerson, played by Walton Goggins.
Ada, played by Diane Ladd.
Jerry, played by Bruce Greenwood.
George, played by Iain Rea.
Sarah, played by Tessa Mitchell.
The World's Fastest Indian is a 2005 New Zealand biographical sports drama film based on the story of New
Zealand speed bike racer Burt Munro and his highly modified 1920 Indian Scout motorcycle.
Munro set numerous land speed records for motorcycles with engines less than 1,000 cc at
the Bonneville Salt Flats in Utah in the late 1950s and into the 1960s.
The film stars Anthony Hopkins, and was produced,
written, and directed by Roger Donaldson.
The film opened on 7 December 2005 in New Zealand to positive reviews, and quickly became the highest grossing local
film at the New Zealand box-office taking in NZ$7,043,000; and taking in over US$18,297,690 worldwide.
The film was theatrically released on 3 February 2006 in the United States by Magnolia Pictures; and
was subsequently released on DVD on 22 December 2006 by Magnolia Home Entertainment.
The film explores themes of utah, new zealand, based on
true story, life's dream, motor sport.
The tone is emotional.